<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../Style/ftid.xsl"?>
<?FTID-ProductionInfo FTID-version="2.8" source-app="IXP4.6"?>
<?FTID-ExportCopyrightStatement Boeing Proprietary. Copyright © Boeing. May be subject to export restrictions under EAR. See title page for details.?>
<!DOCTYPE FrontMatter[<!NOTATION CGM SYSTEM "CGM"><!ENTITY G2-00-01-00_FAA.fm_1710875 SYSTEM "..\Images\2-00-01-00_FAA.fm_1710875.cgm" NDATA CGM>]>
<FrontMatter id="X-BOEING:FTID:81205.787.DDG.PU.FM.2-00-01-00.128638.2-00-01-00_FAA" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.boeing.com/FTID-ML ../Schemas/publishUnits/FrontMatter.xsd" xmlns="http://www.boeing.com/FTID-ML" xmlns:rev="http://www.boeing.com/FTID-ML/Revision" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
<PUMetaData exportControl="Y">
<PUInfo model="787" manualName="Minimum Equipment List (MEL)" manualNumber="787 MEL" chapterNumber="" superSectionNumber="2" sectionName="MEL" chapterName="Introduction" customerName="The Boeing Company" customerCode="VNA" manualCode="DDG" />
<PURevInfo rev:revDate="2025-09-30" rev:revStatus="R" rev:revNumber="10" />
</PUMetaData>
<Introduction id="X-BOEING:FTID:81205.787.DDG.CU.INT.2-00-01-00.128638.2-00-01-00_FAA">
<FMtopic>
<Title>General Notes</Title>
<Para>This section contains the MEL Definitions, the MEL Preamble and all of the MEL items.</Para>
<Para>MEL Items have a table of contents for each ATA.  Each section of information in the MEL has been assigned a unique number and when appropriate, is followed by maintenance or operations information.</Para>
</FMtopic>
<FMtopic>
<Title>
<?FTID-xref 1719412.2-00-01-00_FAA?>MEL Definitions</Title>
<List listType="1.">
<ListItem>
<Para>ATA System Page. The ATA system page is divided into four (4) columns and contains: item and repair category; number installed; number required for dispatch; and remarks or exceptions. Standard ATA categories are used. Items are numbered sequentially.</Para>
<List listType="A.">
<ListItem>
<Para>Item. This column depicts the equipment, system, component, or function listed in the “Item” column.</Para>
</ListItem>
<ListItem>
<Para>Repair Category. See definition #20.</Para>
</ListItem>
<ListItem>
<Para>Number Installed. This column depicts the number (quantity) of instrument and equipment items normally installed in the aircraft. This number represents the aircraft configuration considered in developing this MEL. Should the number be a variable (For example: fleet configuration differences, cockpit lighting items, cabin lighting items, cargo restraint components)
a number is not required and the “-” symbol is used.</Para>
</ListItem>
<ListItem>
<Para>Number Required for Dispatch. This column depicts the minimum number (quantity) of instrument and equipment items required for operation provided the conditions specified in the “Remarks or Exceptions” column are met. Where the MEL shows a variable number required for dispatch, the MEL must reflect the actual number required for dispatch or an alternate means of
configuration control approved by the CAAV.</Para>
</ListItem>
<ListItem>
<Para>Remarks or Exceptions. This column may include a statement(s) either prohibiting or permitting operation with a specific number of instrument and equipment items inoperative, provisos (conditions and limitations) for such operation, and appropriate notes.</Para>
</ListItem>
<ListItem>
<Para>Provisos. Provisos are indicated by a number or a lower case letter in “Remarks or Exceptions”. Provisos are conditions or limitations that must be complied with for operation with the listed instrument or equipment item inoperative.</Para>
</ListItem>
<ListItem>
<Para>Notes provide additional information for crewmember or maintenance consideration. Notes are used to identify applicable material, which is intended to assist with compliance, but do not relieve the aircraft operator of the responsibility for compliance with all applicable requirements. Additional notes may be amended, deleted, or added to the MEL by the aircraft
operator, as appropriate. Notes are not a part of the provisos.</Para>
</ListItem>
<ListItem>
<Para>Vertical Bar (change bar). A vertical bar Indicates a change, addition, or deletion in the adjacent text for the current revision of that page only. All change bars applicable to the previous revision of the MEL are removed prior to the release of the next revision.</Para>
</ListItem>
</List>
</ListItem>
<ListItem>
<Para>AIRPLANE FLIGHT MANUAL (AFM). The FAA-approved AFM is the document approved by the responsible FAA Aircraft Certification Office (ACO) during type certification. The approved flight manual for the specific aircraft is listed on the applicable Type Certificate Data Sheet (TCDS). The approved flight manual is the source document for operational limitations and performance parameters
for an aircraft. The term “approved flight manual” can apply to an AFM. The FAA requires an approved flight manual for aircraft type certification.</Para>
</ListItem>
<ListItem>
<Para>CALENDAR DAY. A 24 hour period from 00:01 to 23:59 based on UTC.</Para>
</ListItem>
<ListItem>
<Para>CONSIDERED INOPERATIVE. The phrase, “Considered Inoperative”, as used in the provisos, means that an instrument and equipment item must be treated for dispatch, taxi and flight purposes as though it were inoperative. The item will not be used or operated until the original deferred item is repaired. Additional actions include: documenting the item on the dispatch
release (if applicable), placarding, and complying with all remarks, exceptions, and related MEL provisions, including any (M) and (O) procedures and observing the repair category.</Para>
</ListItem>
<ListItem>
<Para>CONTINUING AUTHORIZATION:</Para>
<Para>Subject to the approval of the CAAV, Vietnam Airlines may use a procedure for the extension of the applicable Repair Interval B, C for the same duration as specified in the MEL, provided that:</Para>
<Para>- A description of specific duties and responsibilities for controlling extensions is established by the Vietnam Airlines and accepted by the CAAV, and Vietnam Airlines only grants a one-time extension of the applicable Repair Interval, and
- The CAAV is notified of any extension granted within a timescale acceptable to the CAAV, and
- Repair is accomplished at the earliest opportunity.</Para>
</ListItem>
<ListItem>
<Para>DASH (-). Indicates a variable number (quantity) of the instrument and equipment items may be installed or required for dispatch. This is common when a fleet MEL is used since aircraft of the same make and model may have differing numbers of specific instrument and/or equipment items installed.</Para>
</ListItem>
<ListItem>
<Para>DAY OF DISCOVERY. This is the calendar-day an equipment/instrument malfunction was recorded in the aircraft maintenance record/logbook. This day is excluded from the calendar-days or flight-days specified in the MEL for the repair interval of an inoperative instrument and/or equipment item. This provision is applicable to all MEL items; i.e., categories A, B, C,
and D.</Para>
</ListItem>
<ListItem>
<Para>DEACTIVATED AND/OR SECURED. When the MEL refers to an instrument and/or equipment item as deactivated and/or secured, the specified component must be put into an acceptable condition for safe flight. An acceptable method of deactivating and/or securing will be established by Vietnam Airlines.</Para>
</ListItem>
<ListItem>
<Para>DELETED. "Deleted” in the remarks column after a sequence item indicates that the item was previously listed but is now required to be operative if installed in the aircraft.</Para>
</ListItem>
<ListItem>
<Para>EXTENDED RANGE OPERATIONS (ER). ER refers to extended diversion time operations (EDTO) of an airplane with operational approval to conduct EDTO in accordance with the applicable regulations.</Para>
</ListItem>
<ListItem>
<Para>EXCESS ITEMS. Excess items are those instrument and equipment items that have been installed that are redundant to the requirements of the CAAV.</Para>
</ListItem>
<ListItem>
<Para>FLIGHT: For the purpose of an MEL, one “flight” is defined as the period of time that begins the moment at which an aircraft begins to move by its own means in preparation for takeoff, continues during takeoff and the applicable flight phases, and ends when the aircraft lands and comes to a complete stop in its parking area.</Para>
</ListItem>
<ListItem>
<Para>FLIGHT DAY. A flight-day is a 24-hour period (from midnight to midnight) universal coordinated time (UTC), during which at least one flight is initiated for the affected aircraft.</Para>
</ListItem>
<ListItem>
<Para>FLY HOUR: For the purpose of an MEL, the Flight Hours (FHs) are to be counted based on the definition of a Flight, i.e. the period of time that begins the moment at which an aircraft begins to move by its own means in preparation for takeoff, continues during takeoff and the applicable flight phases, and ends when the aircraft lands and comes to a complete stop in
its parking area.
Note: Flight hours as here defined are synonymous with the term “block to block” time or “chock to chock” time in general usage which is measured from the time an aeroplane first moves for the purpose of taking off until it finally stops at the end of the flight.</Para>
</ListItem>
<ListItem>
<Para>HEAVY MAINTENANCE VISIT (HMV). HMV is a scheduled C-check/D-check or airworthiness maintenance program inspection where the aircraft is scheduled to be out of service for 4 or more days.</Para>
</ListItem>
<ListItem>
<Para>ICING CONDITIONS. An atmospheric environment that may cause ice to form on the aircraft (structural) or in the engine(s) (induction).</Para>
</ListItem>
<ListItem>
<Para>INOPERATIVE. A system and/or component malfunction to the extent that it does not accomplish its intended purpose and/or is not consistently functioning normally within its approved operating limit(s) and/or tolerance(s).</Para>
</ListItem>
<ListItem>
<Para>INOPERATIVE COMPONENTS OF AN INOPERATIVE SYSTEM. Inoperative instrument and equipment items, which are components of a system that is inoperative, are usually considered components directly associated with and having no other function than to support that system (warning/caution systems associated with the inoperative system must be operative unless relief is specifically
authorized per the MEL).</Para>
</ListItem>
<ListItem>
<Para>MAIN BASE: Maintenance Base in Ha noi or in Ho Chi Minh.</Para>
</ListItem>
<ListItem>
<Para>IS NOT USED. The phrase “Is Not Used” in the provisos, remarks or exceptions for an MEL instrument or equipment item may specify that another item in the MEL “is not used”. In such cases, crewmembers must not activate, actuate, or otherwise utilize that item under normal operations. It is not necessary for Vietnam Airlines to accomplish the (M) procedure(s) associated
with the item. However, operational requirements must be complied with, and an additional placard must be affixed, to the extent practical, adjacent to the control or indicator for the item that is not used. This informs crewmembers that an instrument or equipment item is not to be used under normal operations.</Para>
</ListItem>
<ListItem>
<Para>NONESSENTIAL EQUIPMENT AND FURNISHINGS (NEF). NEFs are those items installed on the aircraft as part of the original type certification, STC, or other form of alteration that have no effect on the safe operation of flight and would not be required by the applicable certification rules or operational rules. They are those items that, if inoperative, damaged, or missing,
have no effect on the aircraft’s ability to be operated safely under all operational conditions. NEF items are not instrument and equipment items already identified in the MEL or CDL of the applicable aircraft. They do not include instrument and equipment items that are functionally required to meet the certification rule or for compliance with any operational rule.</Para>
</ListItem>
<ListItem>
<Para>OPERATIVE. An operative system and/or component will accomplish its intended purpose and is consistently functioning normally within its design operating limit(s) and tolerance(s). When an MEL item specifies that an item of equipment must be operative, it does not mean that it’s operational status must be verified; it’s to be considered operative unless reported
or known to be malfunctioning. When an MEL item specifies that an item of equipment must be verified operative, it means that it must be checked and confirmed operative at the interval(s) specified for that MEL item. When an MEL item specifies that an item of equipment must be verified but no interval is specified, verification is required only at the time of deferral. Other terminology sometimes
used interchangeably with “operative” within the MEL is “operates normally”, “fully operative”, and “considered operative”. The Vietnamairline's MEL may incorporate standardized terminology of the Vietnam Airlines choice to specify that an item of equipment must be operative, provided the Vietnamairline's MEL definitions indicate that the selected “operative” terminology means that the required
item of equipment will accomplish its intended purpose and is consistently functioning normally within its design operating limit(s) and tolerance(s).</Para>
</ListItem>
<ListItem>
<Para>LONG-RANGE OVER-WATER FLIGHT: a flight on route where the aircraft may be over water at a distance away from land suitable for making an emergency landing corresponding to 120 minutes at cruising speed or 400 NM, whichever is the lesser, applicable to aircraft able to fly to and land at suitable airport, in case one engine becomes inoperative at any point along the
route or planned diversions.</Para>
</ListItem>
<ListItem>
<Para>PLACARDING. Each inoperative instrument or equipment item must be placarded to inform and remind the crewmembers and maintenance personnel of the item condition. To the extent practical, placards should be located adjacent to the control or indicator for the item affected; however, unless otherwise specified (i.e. AFM), placard wording and location will be determined
by Vietnam Airlines.</Para>
</ListItem>
<ListItem rev:revStatus="R" rev:revHighlight="Add Essential Placards/ Markings definition">
<Para>ESSENTIAL PLACARDS / MARKINGS: These include instructional, safety, and system limitation placards/markings that are required by design certification, or that, if misinterpreted, could endanger people,
the aircraft, or adversely affect emergency situations</Para>
<?FTID-rev start?>
<?FTID-rev end?>
</ListItem>
<ListItem>
<Para>REPAIR CATEGORY:</Para>
<List listType="A.">
<ListItem>
<Para>Repair Category A. This category item must be repaired within the time interval specified in the “Remarks or Exceptions” column of Vietnam Airlines’s approved MEL. For time intervals specified in “calendar days” or “flight days”, the day the malfunction was recorded in the aircraft maintenance record/logbook is excluded. For all other time
intervals (i.e., flights, flight legs, cycles, hours, etc.), repair tracking begins at the point when the malfunction is deferred in accordance with Vietnam Airlines’s approved MEL.</Para>
</ListItem>
<ListItem>
<Para>Repair Category B. This category item must be repaired within 3 consecutive calendar-days (72 hours) excluding the day the malfunction was recorded in the aircraft maintenance record/logbook. For example, if it were recorded at 10 a.m. on January 26th, the 3-day interval would begin at midnight the 26th and end at midnight the 29th.</Para>
</ListItem>
<ListItem>
<Para>Repair Category C. This category item must be repaired within 10 consecutive calendar-days (240 hours) excluding the day the malfunction was recorded in the aircraft maintenance record/logbook. For example, if it were recorded at 10 a.m. on January 26th, the 10-day interval would begin at midnight the 26th and end at midnight February 5th.</Para>
</ListItem>
<ListItem>
<Para>Repair Category D. This category item must be repaired within 120 consecutive calendar-days (2880 hours) excluding the day the malfunction was recorded in the aircraft maintenance record/logbook.</Para>
</ListItem>
</List>
</ListItem>
<ListItem>
<Para>REMOTE AREA: Areas in which search and rescue would be especially difficult.</Para>
</ListItem>
<ListItem>
<Para>REQUIRED CABIN ATTENDANT SEAT. A seat in the aeroplane cabin which meets the following conditions.</Para>
<List listType="A.">
<ListItem>
<Para>Where the certification of the cabin requires this seat to be occupied by a qualified cabin crew member as specified in the Operations Manual, and 
This seat is a part of the station to which a qualified cabin crew member is to be assigned for the flight, and 
The qualified cabin crew member assigned to the station is a member of the minimum cabin crew designated for the flight.</Para>
</ListItem>
</List>
</ListItem>
<ListItem>
<Para>REDUCED VERTICAL SEPARATION MINIMUM (RVSM). airspace is any airspace or route between FL 290 and FL 410 (inclusive), where aircraft are vertically separated by 1 000 ft, instead of 2 000 ft. The aircraft system design complies with the design criteria of the JAA Information Leaflet N° 6, and the FAA 91-RVSM Interim Guidance Material for RVSM operations.</Para>
</ListItem>
<ListItem>
<Para>TAKEOFF. Takeoff is the act of beginning a flight in which an aircraft is accelerated from a state of rest to that of flight. For the purposes of MEL relief, this translates to the point at which the pilot physically begins to apply power for the purpose of taking flight.</Para>
</ListItem>
<ListItem>
<Para>TYPE "B" DEFECT.  MEL/Airworthiness related acceptable deferred defects</Para>
</ListItem>
<ListItem>
<Para>VISIBLE MOISTURE. An atmospheric environment containing water, in any form, that can be seen in natural or artificial light; for example, clouds, fog, rain, sleet, hail, or snow.</Para>
</ListItem>
<ListItem>
<Para>VISUAL FLIGHT RULES (VFR). VFR is as defined in 14 CFR Part 91. This precludes a pilot from filing an Instrument Flight Rules (IFR) flight plan.</Para>
</ListItem>
<ListItem>
<Para>VISUAL METEOROLOGICAL CONDITIONS (VMC). VMC means the atmospheric environment is such that would allow a flight to proceed under the visual flight rules applicable to the flight. This does not preclude operating under Instrument Flight Rules.</Para>
</ListItem>
<ListItem>
<Para>(M). This symbol indicates a requirement for a specific maintenance procedure which must be accomplished prior to operation with the listed item inoperative. Normally, these procedures are accomplished by maintenance personnel; however, other personnel may be qualified and authorized to perform certain functions. Procedures requiring specialized knowledge or skill,
or requiring the use of tools or test equipment, should be accomplished by maintenance personnel. The satisfactory accomplishment of all maintenance procedures, regardless of who performs them, is the responsibility of Vietnam Airlines. Appropriate procedures are required to be produced as part of the Vietnam Airlines’s manual or MEL.</Para>
</ListItem>
<ListItem rev:revStatus="R" rev:revHighlight="Add FLIGHT DEFERAL  definition">
<?FTID-rev start?>
<Para>ASTERISK SYMBOL AFTER MEL DISPATCH CONDITION NUMBER:means flight crew may proceed the flight. Refer to MEL judgment by PIC procedure in MEL/CDL application in
FOM.</Para>
<?FTID-rev end?>
</ListItem>
<ListItem>
<Para>ELECTRONIC FAULT ALERTING SYSTEM. New generation aircraft display system fault indications to the flight crew by use of computerized display systems. Aircraft manufacturers incorporate individual design philosophies when determining the data that is represented. The following are customized definitions (specific to each manufacturer)
to help determine the level of messages affecting the aircraft's dispatch status. </Para>
<Para>Definitions for other airplane models are not listed.</Para>
<Para>C. BOEING 787 equipped with Engine Indicating and Crew Alerting Systems (EICAS) provide different priority levels of system messages (WARNING, CAUTION, ADVISORY, STATUS and MAINTENANCE). Any messages that affect airplane dispatch status will be displayed at a STATUS message level or higher. The absence of an EICAS STATUS or higher level (WARNING, CAUTION,
ADVISORY) indicates that the system/component is operating within its approved operating limits or tolerances. System conditions that result only in a maintenance level message, i.e. no correlation with a higher level EICAS message, do not affect dispatch and do not require action other than as addressed within Vietnam Airlines’s standard maintenance program.</Para>
</ListItem>
<ListItem>
<Para>FLAMMABLE/COMBUSTIBLE (MATERIAL). Is defined as material, which is capable of catching fire and burning. When an MEL item specifies the condition that only non-combustible materials are to be carried, all material (including containers, packing material and pallets etc.) in the associated compartments must be of a non-combustible nature. If it cannot be determined whether
any proposed cargo is non-combustible, it must not be loaded in compartments where non-combustible materials are prohibited. Checked baggage, crew baggage and dangerous goods may be combustible, thus they are prohibited.</Para>
</ListItem>
<ListItem>
<Para>AREA NAVIGATION (RNAV) is defined as a method of navigation which permits aircraft operation on desired flight path within the coverage of ground navigation facilities or within the capability of self-contained navigation aids or combination of these.</Para>
<List listType="A.">
<ListItem>
<Para>RNAV 10(RNP 10) Operation Procedures: RNAV 10 is a navigation performance which is a required track-keeping accuracy of ±10NM for at least 95% of flight time.</Para>
</ListItem>
<ListItem>
<Para>RNAV 5(B-RNAV) Operation Procedures: RNAV 5 is a navigation performance which is a required track-keeping accuracy of ±5NM for at least 95% of flight time.</Para>
</ListItem>
<ListItem>
<Para>RNAV 1&amp;2(P-RNAV) Operation Procedures: RNAV 1&amp;2 is a navigation performance which is a required track-keeping accuracy of ±1&amp;2NM for at least 95% of flight time.</Para>
</ListItem>
</List>
</ListItem>
<ListItem>
<Para>RNP-X is requires aircraft performance to a track-keeping accuracy of ± XNM(1(Basic): Terminal, 4 or 10: Oceanic) for at least 95% of flight time. On-board performance monitoring and alerting are required.</Para>
</ListItem>
<ListItem>
<Para>AMM DDG XX-XX-XX means DDG item XX-XX-XX in Aircraft Maintenance Manual (Toolbox).</Para>
<GraphicSet id="X-BOEING:FTID:81205.787.DDG.CU.GR.2-00-01-00.1710843.2-00-01-00_FAA">
<Illustration fileRef="G2-00-01-00_FAA.fm_1710875" linkRef="URN:X-BOEING:FTID:81205.787.DDG.NX.GR.2-00-01-00.1710875." />
</GraphicSet>
</ListItem>
</List>
</FMtopic>
<FMtopic>
<Title>MEL Preamble</Title>
<Para>The VAR require that all equipment installed on an aircraft in compliance with the Airworthiness Standards and the Operating Rules must be operative.  However, the Rules permit the publication of a Minimum Equipment List (MEL) where compliance with certain equipment requirements is not necessary in the interests of safety under all operating conditions.  Experience has
shown that with the various levels of redundancy designed into aircraft, operation of every system or installed component may not be necessary when the remaining operative equipment can provide an acceptable level of safety.  A Master Minimum Equipment List (MMEL) is developed by the FAA, with participation by the aviation industry, to improve aircraft utilization and thereby provide more convenient
and economic air transportation for the public. The FAA approved MMEL includes those items of equipment related to airworthiness and operating regulations and other items of equipment which the Administrator finds may be inoperative and yet maintain an acceptable level of safety by appropriate conditions and limitations; it does not contain obviously required items such as wings, flaps, and rudders.
The MMEL is the basis for development of Vietnam Airlines MEL which take into consideration Vietnam Airlines's particular aircraft equipment configuration and operational conditions. Vietnam Airlines’s MEL, for administrative control, may include items not contained in the MMEL; however, relief for administrative control items must be approved by the CAAV. Vietnam Airlines's MEL may differ
in format from the MMEL, but cannot be less restrictive than the MMEL. The Vietnam Airlines's MEL, when approved and authorized, permits operation of the aircraft with inoperative equipment.</Para>
<Para>Equipment not required by the operation being conducted and equipment in excess of VAR requirements are included in the MEL with appropriate conditions and limitations.  The MEL must not deviate from the Aircraft Flight Manual Limitations, Emergency Procedures or with Airworthiness Directives.  It is important to remember that all equipment related to the airworthiness
and the operating regulations of the aircraft not listed on the MEL must be operative.</Para>
<Para>Suitable conditions and limitations in the form of placards, maintenance procedures, crew operating procedures and other restrictions as necessary are specified in the MEL to ensure that an acceptable level of safety is maintained.</Para>
<Para>The MEL is intended to permit operation with inoperative items of equipment for a period of time until repairs can be accomplished.  It is important that repairs be accomplished at the earliest opportunity.  In order to maintain an acceptable level of safety and reliability the MEL establishes limitations on the duration of and conditions for operation with inoperative
equipment. The MEL provides for release of the aircraft for flight with inoperative equipment. When an item of equipment is discovered to be inoperative, it is reported by making an entry in the Aircraft Maintenance Record/Logbook.  The item is then either repaired or may be deferred per the MEL or other approved means acceptable to the CAAV prior to further operation.  MEL conditions and
limitations, do not relieve Vietnam Airlines from determining that the aircraft is in condition for safe operation with items of equipment inoperative.</Para>
<Para>When these requirements are met, an Airworthiness Release, Aircraft Maintenance Record/Logbook entry, or other approved documentation is issued as prescribed by VAR. Such documentation is required prior to operation with any item of equipment inoperative.</Para>
<Para>Vietnam Airlines is responsible for exercising the necessary operational control to ensure that an acceptable level of safety is maintained.  When operating with multiple inoperative items, the interrelationships between those items and the effect on aircraft operation and crew workload will be considered.</Para>
<Para>MEL inoperative item is defined as any independent item that is considered inoperative under "B Defect" condition (excluding CDL, items with D Repair Interval, items in ATA 25 related to the convenience, comfort, or entertainment of the passengers; and other items that may be caused inoperative as a result of any interface or inter-relationship between previous inoperative
systems or components) Vietnam Airlines is to establish a controlled and sound repair program including the parts, personnel, facilities, procedures, and schedules to ensure timely repair. </Para>
<Para>Maximum permitted inoperative items: Unless otherwise stated, rectification of MEL inoperative items shall be pursued at the first available opportunity not later than three flights or 48 hours elapsed time whichever is sooner. The maximum number of inoperative MEL items with (O) Operational Procedures that can be carried is 4.</Para>
<Para>Vietnam Airlines is to establish a controlled and sound repair program including the parts, personnel, facilities, procedures, and schedules to ensure timely repair.</Para>
<Para>WHEN USING THE MEL, COMPLIANCE WITH THE STATED INTENT OF THE PREAMBLE, DEFINITIONS, AND THE CONDITIONS AND LIMITATIONS SPECIFIED IN THE MEL IS REQUIRED.</Para>
</FMtopic>
</Introduction>
</FrontMatter>