<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../Style/ftid.xsl"?>
<?FTID-ProductionInfo FTID-version="2.8" source-app="IXP4.6"?>
<?FTID-ExportCopyrightStatement Boeing Proprietary. Copyright © Boeing. May be subject to export restrictions under EAR. See title page for details.?>
<!DOCTYPE DispatchItems[<!NOTATION CGM SYSTEM "CGM">]>
<DispatchItems id="X-BOEING:FTID:81205.787.DDG.PU.DI.2-50-11-01.909.2-50-11-01" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.boeing.com/FTID-ML ../Schemas/publishUnits/DispatchItems.xsd" xmlns="http://www.boeing.com/FTID-ML" xmlns:rev="http://www.boeing.com/FTID-ML/Revision" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
<PUMetaData exportControl="Y">
<PUInfo model="787" manualName="Minimum Equipment List (MEL)" manualNumber="787 MEL" chapterNumber="50" superSectionNumber="2" sectionName="MEL" chapterName="Cargo &amp; Accessory Compartments" customerName="The Boeing Company" customerCode="VNA" manualCode="DDG" />
<PURevInfo rev:revDate="2024-06-19" rev:revStatus="U" rev:revNumber="10" />
</PUMetaData>
<MELItem itemNbr="50-11-01" id="X-BOEING:FTID:81205.787.DDG.CU.MEL.2-50-11-01.1.2-50-11-01">
<Title>Lower Cargo Compartment Linings</Title>
<DispatchCondition repairInterval="C" nbrInstalled="-" nbrRequired="-" opsIndicator="(O)">
<DispatchConditionRemarks>
<Para>May be damaged or missing provided procedures are established and used to verify the associated cargo compartment remains empty or contains only ballast, empty cargo handling equipment (ballast may be loaded in ULDs), or fly away kits.</Para>
<Note>
<Para>Operator MELs must define which items are approved for inclusion in the fly away kits and which materials can be used as ballast.</Para>
</Note>
</DispatchConditionRemarks>
<Note>
<Para>Cargo compartment linings include: vertical and sloping sidewall panels; endwall panels; ceiling panels and ceiling equipment support trays; doorway access panels; cargo door panels; decompression door panels; floor panels; equipment and structure enclosures; insulation installed between
linings and airframe or other systems; fasteners attaching linings that are above the floor level; tape sealing liner edges; and bilge endwall/barrier and fire barrier.</Para>
</Note>
<DispatchProcedure>
<OperationProcedure>
<Para>The associated cargo compartment must remain empty, except for ballast, empty cargo containers (ballast may be loaded in ULDs), fly away kits, pallets, and cargo restraint components.    </Para>
<Note>
<Para>Both the aft and bulk cargo compartments must remain empty, except for the listed items, when there are damaged or missing linings in either the aft or the bulk cargo compartment.</Para>
</Note>
</OperationProcedure>
</DispatchProcedure>
</DispatchCondition>
</MELItem>
</DispatchItems>